## George Garcia



Objective: To continue to use my knowledge and experience in Forklift operations to further my professional career. With 5 years of accident free operation and with continuing safety refresher courses, I hope to make a positive addition to any prospective employer. I am also self motivated in learning the correct and current methods of using and operating other lift related equipment (i.e. Pickers, Floor Lifts, etc.)

# Work Experience:

Jense Pre-Cast Company 4801 E. Wyoming St. Tucson, AZ. 85706 (520) 748-1607 2005-2008

Title - Overhead Crane Operator

I am licensed and certified on the overhead crane. My job was to keep ahead of the person making the cement molds. As the crane operator, I had to extract the mold already made and press to the oven table, disengage the mold, lift the mold without damaging the mold, grabbing the new set up which includes, new wire and the pallet (all metal). I would engage and lock and move back to the ready position. I worked with 3 different sized molds and kept the flow steady. I operated the crane from 2005- 2008. I also did other jobs such as driving the water truck, making man holes, box covers, septic tanks, bridges, parking blocks and making the frames for the molds with rebar. I work well with others, am a fast learner, dependable and safety is always first. I am also certified in heavy forklift operation and other heavy equipment.

Weiser Lock Company 6660 S. Broadmoor Ct. Tucson, AZ. 85706 (520) 741-6200 1991-2004

Title - Warehouse Forklift Operator

I am a licensed forklift driver/picker. I can drive all types of forklifts and heavy machinery. I am capable to working the receiving area. I started as an assembly line worker, then moved to the production line as a material handler. From there on to a slow pace line which progressed to a more modern and faster production line. As a picker, I maintained the supplies and support that the production lines required in order to perform their work in a timely and cost effective manner. I went on to set company records for consistency in my work and completing orders on time. I then transferred to the warehouse and learned basic computer skills. I was given the responsibility for the foreign and domestic staging of material shipments. In performing successful and complete shipments, I have learned additional computer skills. I have successfully maintained the duties of being the forklift driver, with an excellent attendance record for 5 years.

Western Lumber Company 3911 N. Highway Dr. Tucson, AZ. 85705 (520) 292-0801 1987-1991

Title - Assistant Foreman

I started as a laborer and moved on to be a truss builder lead because I worked and gave instructions well. I also trained others. My hard work resulted in a promotion to Assistant Foreman. Special orders came directly to me. No job is too big to handle.

Sunnyside School District #12 6115 S. Santa Clara Ave. Tucson, AZ. 85706 1984-1987

(520) 573-9270

· Title - Janitor

I started as a substitute and quickly progressed to being a full time employee. Due to my perfect attendance, excellent work ethic and my ability to work well with others, I was granted the responsibility of Apollo Jr. High School.

## **Sunset Lumber Distribution**

1977-1984

## No longer in business

Title - Salesman

I started behind the counter, then I was privileged to be assigned my own area of the store as a salesman. I sold pre-made cabins, strictly on a commission basis.

# **United States Army**

1974-1977

#### NA

Title - Private

I went into the military branch of the Army as a Private. I specialized in heavy equipment mechanics. I went overseas and was stationed in Germany. I became a Specialist 4, where I was considered a number one mechanic. I worked well with all my colleagues and was in charge of training new personnel. I left the armed forces with an honorable discharge. I received many praises for my time served and deeply regret choosing not to re-enlist.

## Education:

Utterback Middle School

1968-1970

Tucson, AZ

Pueblo High School

1971-1974

Tucson, AZ

Pima Community College

1977-1978

Tucson, AZ

### Personal:

Divorced

Bilingual - Speak Spanish-English

Born: Richgrove, CA, raised in Tucson, AZ

### Additional Information:

I graduated in the top 25 seniors (#19) in my senior class. I am a very easy going guy. I do well with following and giving instructions and feedback. I am comfortable saying "I am an extremely hard worker".

### Hobbies:

I do volunteer work with my Catholic Community Church, I enjoy playing all sports, running, working on old cars (mechanics), carpentry and spending time with my family.